Guide to the Edward James Parrish papers, 1888-1926 and undated RL.00998
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Photograph Albums and Scrapbooks, 1890s-1910s
  - Rosa Parrish's postcards, 1890s-1900s (Box 31)
    Assorted postcards removed for preservation puruposed from their original album and loosely arranged according to depicted location. A large portion originate from Japan, and feature Japanese scenery, artistic greetings, and images from the Russo-Japanese War (1904-1905). Other countries represented include Switzerland, New Zealand, Korea, Czechoslovakia, China, Wales, England, Canada, and Australia. U.S. locations include North Carolina, New York, California, Hawaii, Utah, and others.
  - Untitled album of Parrish family photographs, circa 1899-1905 (Box 11)
    Album with cloth binding, measuring 10 1/2 x 13 1/2 inches. Almost all photographs of the Parrish family in Japan, with some loose photographs laid in. Some prints are duplicate images from other albums in the collection. There are no captions preswent.
  - Untitled album of Parrish family photographs taken in Japan, circa 1899-1905 (Box 22)
    The cloth-covered bound volume measures approximately 11 1/2 x 14 1/2 inches and contains small-format black-and-white family snapshots and some larger souvenir photographs, including some that duplicate those in other albums. Images are not captioned, but appear to be from Japan, China, Niagara Falls, and Durham.
  - Untitled album of Parrish family photographs, circa 1899-1910 (Box 24)
    Album with cloth binding and broken spine, measuring 6 1/2 x 8 inches. Contains personal photographs of the Parrish family, including E. J., Rosa, and Lilly Parrish, largely taken in Japan.
  - Untitled album of Parrish family photographs, circa 1899-1910 (Box 25)
    Embroidered cloth-covered, disbound album, measuring 6 1/2 x 8 inches. Contains hand-tinted souvenir photographs as well as Parrish family photographs. Most of the photographs were taken while the family was in Japan.
- Oversize Materials, 1903-1906 and undated
  - Blueprints of Japan, land surveys, undated (Oversize-folder 3)
    Includes hand-painted blueprints of Tokyo and land surveys from the West Durham Land Company.